{"componentChunkName":"component---src-templates-establishment-page-js","path":"/establishment/5246","result":{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"5246","name":"Jamaica Jamaica Restaurant","address":"17550 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48227","owner":"Sophia Mamby Lincoln","licenseNumber":"260455","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"335","coords":"-83.21558,42.43026","geojson":{"id":"5246","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.2155838,42.43025588]},"properties":{"name":"Jamaica Jamaica Restaurant","owner":"Sophia Mamby Lincoln","address":"17550 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48227","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"260455","establishmentid":"5246","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"335","most_recent_license_date":null}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"1993","name":"Jamaica, Jamaica","address":"17550 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"352","name":"Lon's Coney Island","address":"17501 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"51622648","name":"Great Lakes Sport Bar","address":"17602 Seven Mile W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"5107","name":"Mighty Sub Shop","address":"17602 W. Seven Mile","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"3385","name":"Hamlin's BBQ","address":"17602 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"1912","name":"Fish & Chicken Land","address":"17602 Seven Mile Rd. W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"51623779","name":"Dominiques Soul Food","address":"17341 Seven Mile W","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"4494","name":"Temptations Grill","address":"17256 Seven Mile W.","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"51622600","name":"Mr. Corn Beef","address":"17819 W. Seven Mile Rd. 48235","zipcode":"48235"},{"establishmentid":"2018","name":"Coffey K-8","address":"17210 Cambridge","zipcode":"48235"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"56709","inspectionDate":"2021-11-18T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.4119","violationDescription":"Sec. 4119. (1) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), a person licensed as a food establishment under this chapter shall keep a copy of the current license or temporary license furnished by the department posted and exposed in a conspicuous place for public inspection. A conspicuous place is the principal place where food business is transacted.  (2) In the case of vending machines, the name and address and telephone number of the current vending machine location operator shall be conspicuously displayed on each vending machine.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"displayed","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"54737","inspectionDate":"2021-04-15T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"5-202.13","violationDescription":"An air gap between the water supply inlet and the flood level rim of the PLUMBING FIXTURE, EQUIPMENT, or nonFOOD EQUIPMENT shall be at least twice the diameter of the water supply inlet and may not be less than 1 inch. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Air gap","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"PREP SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"PREP SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.4119","violationDescription":"Sec. 4119. (1) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), a person licensed as a food establishment under this chapter shall keep a copy of the current license or temporary license furnished by the department posted and exposed in a conspicuous place for public inspection. A conspicuous place is the principal place where food business is transacted.  (2) In the case of vending machines, the name and address and telephone number of the current vending machine location operator shall be conspicuously displayed on each vending machine.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"displayed","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.114","violationDescription":"The PREMISES shall be free of items that are unnecessary to the operation or maintenance of the establishment such as EQUIPMENT that is nonfunctional, no longer used and free of litter.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Unnecessary item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not removed from facility","subProblem":"","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.13","violationDescription":"POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be thawed:  Under refrigeration, or under cool running water (<70° F), or as part of cooking process, and total accumulated time above 41° F, for thawed portions, shall not exceed 4 hours.  Any thawing procedure may be used for immediate service for individual consumers order of READY-TO-EAT foods.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Frozen food(s) for thawing","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F thawed or partially thawed","subProblem":"","location":"PREP SINK","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2021-04-16T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"50648","inspectionDate":"2020-02-03T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \n\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ready to eat, potentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Beyond consume by date","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2020-02-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOKING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2020-02-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2020-02-04T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-101.11","violationDescription":"Materials for indoor floor, wall, and ceiling surfaces under conditions of normal use shall be:\n(1) SMOOTH, durable, and EASILY CLEANABLE for areas where FOOD ESTABLISHMENT operations are conducted;\n(2) Closely woven and EASILY CLEANABLE carpet for carpeted areas; and\n(3) Nonabsorbent for areas subject to moisture such as FOOD preparation areas, walk-in refrigerators, WAREWASHING areas, toilet rooms, mobile FOOD ESTABLISHMENT SERVICING AREAS, and areas subject to flushing or spray cleaning methods.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Ceiling material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not easily cleanable","subProblem":"","location":"CEILING","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"44723","inspectionDate":"2019-01-03T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"DISHWASHING AREA","subLocation":"Inside the KITCHEN","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Non-food contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"VENTILATION HOOD SYSTEM","subLocation":"Inside the KITCHEN","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"2-102.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall demonstrate this knowledge by compliance with this Code, by being a certified FOOD protection manager who has shown proficiency of required information through passing a test that is part of an ACCREDITED PROGRAM, or by responding correctly to the inspector's questions as they relate to the specific FOOD operation. (Pf)","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not ensuring compliance","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Inside the Facility","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Person-in-charge must ensure compliance with items listed above."},{"violationCode":"8-304.11","violationDescription":"Upon acceptance of the PERMIT issued by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY, the PERMIT HOLDER in order to retain the PERMIT shall:\n(A) Post the PERMIT in a location in the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT that is conspicuous to CONSUMERS; \n(B) Comply with the provisions of this Code including the conditions of a granted VARIANCE as specified under § 8-103.12, and APPROVED plans as specified under § 8-201.12;\n(C) If a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT is required under § 8-201.13 to operate under a HACCP PLAN, comply with the plan as specified under § 8-103.12;\n(D) Immediately contact the REGULATORY AUTHORITY to report an illness of a FOOD EMPLOYEE or CONDITIONAL EMPLOYEE as specified under ¶ 2-201.11(B); \n(E) Immediately discontinue operations and notify the REGULATORY AUTHORITY if an IMMINENT HEALTH HAZARD may exist as specified under § 8-404.11;\n(F) Allow representatives of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY access to the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT as specified under § 8-402.11;\n(G) Except as specified under ¶ (H) of this section, replace existing facilities and EQUIPMENT specified in § 8-101.10 with facilities and EQUIPMENT that comply with this Code if:\n(1) The REGULATORY AUTHORITY directs the replacement because the facilities and EQUIPMENT constitute a public health HAZARD or nuisance or no longer comply with the criteria upon which the facilities and EQUIPMENT were accepted,\n(2) The REGULATORY AUTHORITY directs the replacement of the facilities and EQUIPMENT because of a change of ownership, or\n(3) The facilities and EQUIPMENT are replaced in the normal course of operation;\n(H) Upgrade or replace refrigeration EQUIPMENT as specified under Subparagraph 3-501.16(A)(2)(b), if the circumstances specified under Subparagraphs (G)(1) - (3) of this section do not occur first, and 5 years pass after the REGULATORY AUTHORITY adopts this Code;\n(I) Comply with directives of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY including time frames for corrective actions specified in inspection reports, notices, orders, warnings, and other directives issued by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY in regard to the PERMIT HOLDER'S FOOD ESTABLISHMENT or in response to community emergencies; \n(J) Accept notices issued and served by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY according to LAW; and \n(K) Be subject to the administrative, civil, injunctive, and criminal remedies authorized in LAW for failure to comply with this Code or a directive of the REGULATORY AUTHORITY, including time frames for corrective actions specified in inspection reports, notices, orders, warnings, and other directives.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"Inside the Facility","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"41019","inspectionDate":"2017-12-10T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"37495","inspectionDate":"2016-12-14T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2023-04-25T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"5246"}},"staticQueryHashes":["3649515864","63159454"]}